T3 not working. I have tried from 20 to
75 micrograms daily all in the AM fasted
split amm different doses. Best protocol
for fat
loss. Yeah. So I have seen synthetic
thyroid hormones. So we're talking about
thyroid treatment. Synthetic and you can
have something be synthetic and still be
bioididentical. I think people kind of
get these things confused. So T3 and or
T4 are synthetic bioididentical thyroid
hormone kind of like the thyroid version
of testosterone. Um and then natural
desecated thyroid in the context of a
prescription uh comes from a pig's
thyroid but it is standardized to have
T3 T4 as well as other thyroid hormones
and enzymes and signaling molecules in
it as well. So, one of the issues with
the synthetic thyroid treatments is that
some guys just don't respond to them.
Um, and in these instances, like I've
seen guys come into to my clinics with
taking 200, 300, 400 micrograms of T4,
50, 100 micrograms of T3, and their
levels barely move. And, you know,
they'll still be taking it on an empty
stomach. They'll make sure to not have
any coffee or anything else with it to
compromise absorption. it's coming from
the pharmacy. You know, they've, you
know, checked every option. A lot of
guys get a really poor response to this.
A lot of guys get a fantastic response.
I mean, this is not, you know, a common
thing, but I would say a decent
percentage of guys are nonresponders to
synthetic T3, T4, and when they swap to
natural desecated thyroid, the
prescription version, they get a much
better response. Now, there are also
cases for vice versa. There are also
guys who don't absorb and respond to the
NDT and they have a fantastic response
to synthetic. So, it's very important
for practitioners to have both in the
toolbox. Um, I think that on average
more people respond better to natural
desecated thyroid. That's just what I've
seen. But the this is, you know,
assuming that this is a pharmaceutical
grade product. I'm skeptical that it is
because you're using it for fat loss. Uh
so firstly, you know, you could just be
taking a sugar pill, but let's
hypothetically say that it is a uh
pharmaceutical grade thyroid
preparation. Um yeah, it is possible
that you're having a very low response
to this and a non-significant response.
Um in terms of like best protocol for
fat loss, the best protocol for fat loss
is diet and exercise. Um, I'm not in the
camp of uh using these hormones in this
way purely for the sake of a do no harm
approach. I know it's like a bit of like
a party pooper fuddy duddy kind of
response, but I'm hyperconservative in
my recommendations. With that said, I
think that if someone is going to use a
stimulant to like cut weight, let's say
like you're cutting weight for like a
professional fight or
something, boosting thyroid hormone is
probably safer than using things like
clen or you know, whatever else people
are using like highdose ECA stack like I
think people are still using that. So,
you know, supporting optimal thyroid
function for fat loss is probably on the
safer side. But there is there will be
hell will freeze over before I come
online and recommend a standard dose of
thyroid hormone for fat loss. It's just
not something I'm going to do.